How far would you go, how much would you sacrifice
to get back what you have lost?
The Missing is a thriller, western, adventure film directed by Ron Howard.
When rancher and single mother of two Maggie Gilkeson sees her teenage daughter, Lily, kidnapped by Apache rebels,
she reluctantly accepts the help of her estranged father, Samuel, in tracking down the kidnappers.
Along the way, the two must learn to reconcile the past and work together if they are going to have any hope
of getting Lily back before she is taken over the border and forced to become a prostitute.
Maggie Gilkeson, played by Cate Blanchett.
Samuel Jones, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Lilly Gilkeson, played by Evan Rachel Wood.
Dot Gilkeson, played by Jenna Boyd.
Brake Baldwin, played by Aaron Eckhart.
Lt. Jim Ducharme, played by Val Kilmer.
The Missing is a 2003 American Western film directed by Ron Howard
and starring Tommy Lee Jones and Cate Blanchett.
It is based on Thomas Eidson's 1995 novel The Last Ride.
Set in 1885 New Mexico Territory, the film is notable for the authentic use of the Apache
language by various actors, some of whom spent long hours studying it.
It was produced by Revolution Studios, Imagine Entertainment, and Daniel Ostroff
Productions and distributed by Columbia Pictures (Sony Pictures Releasing).
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of daughter, mexico, based on
novel or book, new mexico, apache nation.
The tone is intense.